Contact

fcasarotti@outlook.com

www.linkedin.com/in/franciscocasarotti (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Python SQL

Microsoft Power BI

Francisco Casarotti

Software Engineer - Python | SQL | Power BI | ETL Uruguay

Summary

Software Engineer with 4+ years of experience specializing in Python, ETL, SQL, and Power BI.

I'm good at turning data into insights, building data pipelines, and making information accessible through clear visuals. Always looking for new challenges to drive impact with data-driven solutions.

Experience

Servicio Central de Informática | SeCIU Data Engineer/ DNS Administrator May 2022 - Present (2 years 6 months) Montevideo, Uruguay

As a DNS Administrator and Data Engineer, I am responsible for designing and managing databases, writing SQL queries, and developing Python scripts for ETL processes and data quality validation. I leverage Pentaho for advanced data analysis and develop internal applications using Python to streamline workflows, such as providing quick solutions to recurring queries and automating information extraction processes. Additionally, I manage both Unix and Windows environments and oversee the deployment of critical applications on Unix servers, utilized by NICUY for domain registration.

EL TÚNEL - TU FARMACIA

Data Engineer

January 2023 - Present (1 year 10 months)

Database Modeling and Creation: Designing schemas, normalizing data, and creating relational databases.

ETL: Implementing Extraction, Transformation, and Loading processes to integrate data from multiple sources, clean it, and prepare it for analysis. Python scripts for process automation: Developing Python scripts to automate tasks such as data cleaning, validation, and real-time processing, ensuring data persistence in databases.

Power BI: Creating interactive dashboards and dynamic reports by connecting various data sources to extract key insights of sales through visualizations.

Windows Server management: Administering and maintaining a Windows server.

Web app development with Flask: Web App application developed using Python's Flask framework for a customizable way of processing dynamic data.

Universidad de la República IT Technician December 2019 - February 2022 (2 years 3 months)

Montevideo, Uruguay

I have conducted database queries and log analysis for troubleshooting, managed the installation and administration of Unix and Windows servers, and configured and maintained firewalls to ensure secure and efficient infrastructure operations.

Other responsibilities included user creation and maintenance, IT support, data cabling surveys, assembling new cables, and identifying new network outlets.

ICG

IT Technician

August 2018 - December 2019 (1 year 5 months)

Montevideo, Uruguay

Server and database management oriented to the program provided by the company.

Good client relationship management. Installation of servers and workstations for clients

Installation and management of Windows and Linux servers, as well as firewall configuration.

Academia Guerrafont Professor June 2017 - June 2018 (1 year 1 month)

Pocitos

High school mathematics and physics teacher.

Education

Facultad de ingenieria UDELAR - Ingeniería en Computación Ingeniería, Ingeniería de software